TIRAYR KARAPETYAN

(C) +374 98 62 6627 | tir1kar@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Data Engineer with more than 6 years of Educational and Work experiences.

Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analysis of data.

Excellent understanding of data management systems and data design.

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 20 April, 1995 Place of Birth: Ashtarak, Armenia Nationality: Armenian Marital status: single

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tirayr-karapetyan-471078111/

GitHub: https://github.com/Tirayr

Core Skills

MySQL/MSSQL (advanced level querying. data cleansing, stored procs, ETL pipelines, DBA operations)

Python (data normalization, data scrapping, process automation, graphical interface, data analysis, data processing pipelines)

Bash (advanced scripting, process automation, monitoring tools, data processing pipelines)

AWS (S3, EC-2, IAM, EBS, EFS

CodeCommit, CLI, etc.)

GCP (DataProc, BigQuery, Composer, GCS,

Compute Engine, VPC, IAM, etc.)

Apache products (PySpark, Airflow, Hive)

Terraform (AWS and GCP providers)

Teamwork, interpersonal & business communication, Team leading, problem solving, ability to work under pressure, purposeful, flexible, attentive, time management, schedule management, self-confidence public speaking

Other Skills

K8s, CircleCI, GIT, Linux, Perl(basic), Java(basic), EViews, Stata, MS office, Windows, Finance, micro(macro)economics

Work History

Senior Data Engineer SADA

08/2022 till now

- Designing, implementing, and running big data pipelines that canvas over petabytes of data
- Actively participate in the architecture, design, and implementation discussions
- Actively participate in planning, execution, and success of complex technical projects
- Participation in Spark job migration projects as well as Airflow pipelines
- Participation in infrastructure migration projects from on-prem/aws to gcp
- Development of CI/CD pipelines (CircleCI, ArgoCD, K8s, etc.) for the clients

Senior Data Engineer 07/2018 to 08/2022

OneMarketData

- Daily meetings and discussions in a technical field speaking English
- Daily financial researches
- Strong proficiency in database management (MySQL dbs, onetick dbs, reference dbs)
- Proficient in writing and optimizing SQL statements
- Data performance and availability speed optimization
- Fluency in using code versioning tool GIT/GitLab
- Writing shell scripts as a part of the process and usage in crontab
- Fluency in working in Linux environment
- Developing processes in AWS
- Python usage for solving different kind of data problems (scrapping, data normalization-parsing)
- Maintaining onetick servers
- Ability to works well in a team environment and communicating with cross-functional teams and teams that are geographically diverse.
- Technical investigation calls with clients
- Daily work with terraform to manage infrastructure as a code

Programmer Analyst 02/2018 to 07/2018

Makichyan Consulting LLC – Yerevan, Yerevan

- Write queries using SQL (filtering, cleaning, preparing)
- Sorting Data using SQL (ABC, XYZ analysis)
- Integration using SQL
- Python (creating graphical interface, working with data Connect SQL with Python)
- Analyzing data and developing models for improving client company's profit

Administrator/Receptionist

12/2015 to 12/2017

Envoy Hostel & Tours | Yerevan – Yerevan, Yerevan

- Greeted incoming customers in a professional manner and provided friendly, knowledgeable assistance.
- · Corresponded with clients through email, telephone, or postal mail

Certifications

Google Cloud Certified Professional Data Engineer
Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect

Education

Yerevan State University - Yerevan, Yerevan

Bachelor: Actuarial Science

Graduation on 2018 Graduation on 2020

Masters: Finance

- Top 5% of class
- GPA 16/20
- Associated works:

Coursework (Titles) "Markov Chain", "Time Series:ARMA model:Bitcoin Forecasting"

Bachelor Graduatework (Title) "Kalman Filter: Exchange Rate Forecasting"

Masters Graduatework (Title) "Impact of financial news sentiment on market direction"

Languages

Armenian (native)

English(fluent)

Russian(fluent)

Interests

Finance, Reading, Mathematics, Econometrics, Data architecture, Data analysis, Machine Learning, Watching Football, Music